Guide to the Washington Writers' Archive and Splendid Wake records, 1968 - 2019 MS2321
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Washington Writers' Archive and Splendid Wake records
1968-2019
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2321
1 Linear Feet
This collection contains programs, lists, a cd, meeting minutes, posters,and broadsides. These materials came to Special Collections from members of the dc poetry community. Not one donation were enough for a stand-alone collection. This collection was created by Special Collections staff as one location to store these materials with like content. This artificial collection was formed in 2013, but the material dates from 1968-2019.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Records and Oversize records
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This artificial collection was started following the first Splendid Wake event September 25, 2013. It will be added to periodically by anyone who has material that document the dc poetry community, but not enough material to form an individual collection.
This collection will continue to receive donations.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains programs, lists, a cd, meeting minutes, posters,and broadsides. These materials came to Special Collections from members of the dc poetry community. No one donation was enough for a stand-alone collection. This artificial collection was created by Special Collections staff to serve as one collection to store these materials with like content and subject matter. The collection was formed in 2013, but the material dates from 1968-2019.
Biographical / Historical
The Washington Writers' Archive (WWA) is a collecting area of the Special Collections Research Center. The WWA is meant to gather personal papers and organization's records to provide archival collections for in-depth study of the Washington literary community. The Washington Writers' Archive encompasses many personal papers of local dc poets as well as the records of reading series and publishing houses. The Splendid Wake was an event to bring together poets to share their memories of the DC poetry community. When DC poets have material to share that does not constitute a stand alone collection it will become part of this collection.
DC Poetry Wiki
The Splendid Wake created and added content to an online wikipedia instance for DC Poetry. That site was hosted by George Washington University. In 2021 the wiki was frozen and a web archive of the content generated.
DC Poetry: A Splendid Wake wiki
Poetry -- 20th century; Poetry; Poetry -- 21st century
- Records, 1968-2019; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Intellectually arranged alphabetically. Physically arrangement follows when folders are added to the box. Thus folder 12 is intellectually arranged after folder 2.
  - AAFSW News, 1990 February; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General
    Association of American Foreign Service Women. On page 5 there is a photograph and a small write-up about the AAFSW Writer's Groups having a combined get-together at Ingeborg C. Miller's home. Miller is a local poet.
  - Aleph Vol 1, No. 1, 1975; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Article by Jack Foley describing the sudden eruption of Washington poetry, 1968-1975
  - Andrew Oerke biographical data, 1985-2009; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    The file contains a photocopy of the publication Children of Hunger by Andrew Oerke
    Separated Materials
    The book Never seek to tell thy love a love odyssey was moved to the Special Collections stacks.
  - Blessings by Ginger Ingalls, 2013; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3, Cd 1)
  - Fliers for various poetry groups, 2016-2018; Series 19 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hartworks (The Charles Hart Middle School Literary Magazine), 2017 Winter; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Image of Collective Voices (Andre "Brenardo" Taylor, Sylvia Dianne "Ladi Di" Beverly, and Joy "Sistah Joy" Alford, 2017; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Little mags and independent presses in DC Area, 2013; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    a list compiled by Merrill Leffler
  - McComb Street book launch, Circa 1980 - Circa 2005; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    As described by Elisavietta Ritchie these two lists of attendees were from book launches at her house on McComb Street in Washington DC.
  - Green-winged Horse, 2013 October 13; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    An evening at the Embassy of Bulgaria honoring the inspired poetry of Lyubomir Levchev. This was sponsored by the William Meredith Foundation.
  - Poetry events/readings at Gelman Library, 2008-2009; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Scope and Contents
    The format of the recordings is dvd. There are two events in this folder. One was a poetry reading by Kwame Alexander held on September 17, 2008 and the other is untitled, but dated April 9, 2009.
  - Splendid Wake sign-up book, 2013-2018; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    This book recorded some of the attendees at the Splendid Wake events. At this time the book includes four events September 25 2013, March 21, 2014, March 20, 2015, March 18, 2016, and March 18, 2018
  - Splendid Wake program: Grace Cavalieri's remarks, 2013 September 25; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Splendid Wake programs, 2013-2019; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    There are programs in this folder covering 2013-2019
  - Splendid Wake recording of programs (programs 1, 4 - 6), 2013 September 25 - 2017 - 2018 March 25; Series 1 (Box 1, Dvd 1)
  - That Word by CeLillianne Green materials and fliers from other events and readings, 2015 June 21 - 2017; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Gift of CeLillianne Green, 2015 August 26, (2015.045) and 2017 May 30 (2017.027)
  - Tuesdays at Two Poetry Collective, 2008-2015; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Gift of Kathleen Finn Jordan February 24, 2015 (2015.016). Addition by Peter Lattu of program for 2015 event.
  - Washington Poetry Center, 1970-1973; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Gift of Rod Jellema
  - Word Wrights No. 30, 2006 April; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Oversize records, Series 2
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Splendid Wake poster, 2013 September 25; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Writers Here and Now reading series, Circa 1980; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Poetry and the National Conscience, 1968-1970; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - The Poet of Washington by John Pauker, 1977; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)